md and ceo of the company
mr gopal balachandran cfo and cro
mr sanjeev mantri executive director
retail and mr alok agarwal executive
director wholesale
as a reminder all participant lines will
be in the listen only mode
and there will be an opportunity for you
to ask questions after the presentation
concludes
should you need assistance during the
call please signal an operator by
pressing star then zero on your
touchstone phone
please note that this conference is
being recorded
i now have the conference over to mr
bhargava gupta
thank you and over to you sir
thank you raymond uh good evening to
each one of you
um thank you for joining the earnings
conference call of ics lombard
for q2 fi 21 and h12
2021 i hope you and all your colleagues
are safe and healthy
so what i'll do is i'll give you a brief
overview of the industry trends and
developments that we've
witnessed in the last few months post
this rca for mr gopal balachandran will
share the financial performance
of the company if you look at the
macro environment of the last couple of
quarters
was the sharp correction in the economy
in q1 economic activity has started to
pick up
with high frequency indicators such as
electric regeneration
fast actual collections e-way bills air
freight
export and motor vehicle registrations
touching pre-covered levels towards the
end of q2
in addition to the normalization and
economic activity pent-up demand and
restocking may have led to this kind of
improvement
so we have to wait and see if this
sustains post the festive season
there are many headwinds to reaching a
level of meaningful growth
for the economy such as the risk of
resurgence of covert cases
yet disrupted supply chains uh aggregate
customer demand
and the large contractions still seen in
certain specific sectors
the gi industry has been able to
navigate the current macro and
environment better
with industry gdpi in the recent months
moving closer to
pre-covet levels segments such as motor
insurance have shown signs of recovery
driven by
improving rural sentiment and growing
need for personal mobility and safety
concerns
health insurance continues to register
robust growth given the regulatory
tailwinds and heightened awareness about
the need for protection
as far as the commercial lines are
concerned the fire segment continued to
grow show rover's growth
aided by rate hike that came into force
on first january of
this year while marine and engineering
lines witnessed
degrowth at isis lombard we remain
confident that the industry will
continue to outperform in terms of
growth given the new the low insurance
penetration
urbanization of population and now
increased
increasingly enhanced risk awareness
speaking of the performance of the
industry as per the gi council report
the gi industry registered a growth of
1.4 percent
for h1 2021 over h120
with the industry gdpr moving to 968.32
billion
in h121 from 951.28 billion in h1 2020.
excluding the crop segment this growth
would would have been a 2.8 percent
for the quarter the overall growth and
growth excluding crop segment was 5.6
percent and 9.2
respectively the combined ratio of the
industry was 104.4
in 0.4 in q1 2021 as compared to 113.1
percent in q1 2020
based on available information from
public disclosures excluding two
companies which haven't disclosed their
numbers as yet
further the overall combined ratio from
private multi-line general insurance
where
was about 103.0 in q1 2021 as compared
to 107.7 in q1 2020.
as i have mentioned earlier the
regulator has proactively announced
several note noteworthy
measures including relaxations and
regulations promoting ease of doing
business particularly in terms of the
digital
agenda during the quarter on september
4th the authority also issued guidelines
on wellness and preventive features
where an insurance may
insurers may offer reward points to
customers
meeting set criteria these features can
be offered as an
add-on or optional cover this will
enable insurers to endeavor to promote
wellness offerings like discounts and
increase discounts on increase in some
insured discounts on opt services
redeemable voucher on health supplements
or gmail memberships etc
this is also expected to expand the
scope for the insurers providing
wellness and valuated offerings to their
customers
let me now turn to the claims behavior
observed in the recent months
the motor od claim frequency has been
gradually increasing since the lifting
of the lockdown
and has now reached almost pre-covered
levels
similarly in case of health claim
frequency has seen a surge in elective
surgeries
as you know they are resuming though it
continues to remain below pre-covert
levels
the spike in covet cases reported across
the country had
seen elevated levels in end of september
and since then we have seen a slight
moderation
for the overall industry covert claims
reported as on 30th september 2021
2020 was uh 3.24 lakhs of which 17 000
covert claims were reported with icc
combat
the elevated levels in covet uh cases
remain a cause for concern for the whole
industry and may have an adverse
impact on the loss ratios of the health
insurance portfolio this year
particularly if the upcoming festive
season gatherings lead to a second wave
of
claims we expect that this increase
would be only partially offset by the
reduced number of non-covered claims on
the health side
however given the strength of a
well-diversified product mix
and discipline underwriting we believe
that at ica salomon we are reasonably
placed
as far as our overall claims cost for
the year is concerned
in current times the other major trend
is the significant increase in adoption
of digital solutions by consumers
at icc lombard we have been continuously
investing in this on this front for the
last 15 years
in the previous earnings call we had
shared with you some of our efforts
towards getting more customers channel
partners and other stakeholders to avail
our digital
platforms we continue with this drive in
the quarter under review
over 97.5 percent of policies issued by
us
in the first half of this year were
sourced through these digital solutions
where we did not see paper with regard
to claim settlement
sixty three point one percent of our
motor od claims were serviced through
live video streaming uh app instruct in
september to twenty twenty
up from twenty four point five percent
in march twenty twenty uh this feature
does away with the need for physically
surveying
a damaged vehicle allowing real-time
claim settlement
and approval we continue to
invest in new technologies on the
digital front including ai
and ml that help in policy issuance
claims
fraud control and servicing our
automated ai solution
processed three times the motor break in
sales inspections in september as
compared to march 2020.
on the health insurance fund under group
health policies 60.9
of the fresh cashless requests by were
authorized by our ai
ml engage you know the solution that as
compared to 31
in march 2020 tele underwriting has
become an important tool during this
pandemic and 15
of our medical tele underwriting were
processed straight through
using a voice enabled ai and nlp
solution
our mobile app i'll take care which has
features such as hello doctor chat with
experts
emergency medical assessment and health
risk assessment has crossed 2 lakh
downloads
enabling more and more customers to
avail our insurance and wellness
solutions at their fingertips
we continue to add digital capabilities
in servicing
including process of endorsements since
its launch last year 60
of all group health endorsements are now
done digitally reducing processing time
from weeks to minutes
and twenty four percent percent of motor
policy endorsements from the agency
channel are processed real time using
our digital
solutions you know one of our beliefs
has been that slowdowns are the best
time to invest for the long term
uh during recent months despite the
challenging economic environment
we have made significant investments in
improving our digital and people
capabilities
we have also accelerated our digital
engagement initiatives for employees
that focus on
all-round well-being we believe
technology-led innovation coupled with
dynamic workforce will lead to a
you know to benefiting us in the long
term uh and us to capture the
opportunity that
the sector offers our endeavor comes
from our long-standing customer
relationships that we've been able to
sustain even through this pandemic
we are constantly evolving our
strategies to further consider our
position in the non-life
insurance segment we continue to remain
focused on creating long-term value for
our tech stakeholders through prudent
risk selection
and sustained profitability i will now
ask gopal to take you through the
financial numbers for the recently
concluded quarter
thanks bhagav and uh good evening to
each one of you
i will now give you a brief overview of
the financial performance of the company
for quarter 2 and h1 2021
we have put up the results presentation
on our website you can access it as we
walk you through the performance numbers
the gdpr of the company should have
64.91 billion in h1 2021 as compared to
64.4 billion in s21 2020
a growth of 0.8 compared to industry
growth of 1.4 percent
excluding the crop segment gdp increased
to 64.59 billion
in this first half as compared to 63.86
billion
in h1 2020 registering a growth of 1.1
compared to the industry growth of 2.8
on a quarterly basis
the gdp grew by 8
over quarter 2 last year compared to the
industry growth of five point six
percent
if you were to exclude the crop segment
the gdp growth for quarter two twenty
twenty one was nine point nine percent
over quarter two twenty twenty four s as
compared to the industry growth of nine
point two percent for the same period
our focus on preferred segments
primarily drove our gdpa growth
consequent to the increase in minimum
prescribed rates for certain occupancies
under fire segment this portfolio
registered a robust
gdpa growth of 47.6 in h1 2021
thereby catalyzing the gdp growth of our
property and casualty segment
as indicated in our results presentation
the overall property and casualty
segment grew by twenty point five
percent for h1 2021
over h1 2020 on the retail side of the
business
sme and agency channel and health
indemnity continued to grow faster
and remain our areas of focus motor
segment that saw negative growth in the
last quarter
registered a growth of nine point four
percent in quarter to twenty twenty
to harness the potential of the segments
we have been expanding our distribution
network to increase penetration entire
three entire four cities
our agents including the point of sale
distribution increased to fifty two
thousand seven eighty five
as on september 30 2020 from 49802 as on
june 30 2020.
during the quarter we also announced
entering into a bank assurance tie-up
with
yes bank the advanced premium numbers
was 31.60 billion as at september 30
which is up from 30.31 billion as on
june 33 2020. during the quarter
we entered we are now entering into a
scheme of arrangement with bharti axa
to acquire the non-life insurance
business in relation to the scheme the
expenses
incurred of about 0.31 billion
have been charged in the p l during
quarter 2
and h1 2021 we are excited and looking
forward for realization of the long term
business potential that this scheme
entails our combined ratio stood at 99.8
percent in
h1 2021 compared to 101.5 in h1 2020
despite the cyclone and flood losses
excluding the impact of cyclone and
flood losses of
0.77 billion the combined ratio stood at
98.2 in h1 2021 as against 100.1 percent
in h1 2020
excluding the impact of cyclone and
flood losses of 0.61 billion
combined ratios stood at 99.7 percent in
q2
f5 2021 compared to 102.6 percent in q2f
by 2020
here again excluding the impact of
cyclone and flood losses
which was point four six billion for
this quarter two
the combined ratio stood at ninety seven
point nine percent
as against hundred point seven percent
in q2 fy 2020
again excluding the impact of cyclone
and flood losses which was
0.45 billion our investment assets
rose to 291.62 billion at september 30
as compared to 281.18 billion at june 30
2020.
our investment leveraged net of
borrowings was 4.13 at september 30
this year as compared to 4.23 at june 30
2020.
investment income increased to 10.91
billion in this first half as compared
to 10.14 billion in
first half of last year on a quarterly
basis investment income increased to
5.92 billion
in quarter to this year as compared to
4.87 billion in quarter to
last financial year our capital gains
was 1.84 billion
in h1 2021 as compared to 2.07 billion
in h1 2020
capital gains in quarter to 2021 was
1.24 billion
as compared to 0.69 billion in quarter
to fbi 2020
our profit before tax grew by 15.9
percent
to 10.86 billion in h1 2021 as compared
to 9.36 billion in h1 2020
whereas pbt grew by 20.3 percent to 5.55
billion in q2f521
as compared to 4.61 billion and q2f by
2020.
consequently profit after tax grew by
31.7
to 8.14 billion in h1 2021 as compared
to 6.18 billion in h1 2020
whereas profit after tax grew by 35
percent
to 4.16 billion and q2 fbi 2021
as compared to 3.08 billion in q2f by
2020.
primarily due to the lower effective tax
rate of 25.03
return on average equity was 24.9
percent in h1 2021
as compared to 22.3 percent in h1 2020
the roe for q2 2021 was twenty four
point seven percent
as compared to twenty two percent in q2
fy 2020
solvency ratio was healthy at 2.74 times
at september 30 2020 as against 2.5
times
at june 30 2020 continued to be higher
than the minimum
regulatory requirement of 1.5 times as i
conclude
i would like to reiterate that we ended
quarter 2
and h1 2021 with healthy financials
as a company we are evolving our
strategies with an overarching objective
of creating long-term value for all our
stakeholders
whether it is initiatives towards
enhancing technology capabilities
or attracting talented employees icc
lombard has always strived to be at the
forefront of
investing in sustainable ways of doing
business and would continue to do so
while we are excited by the opportunity
in the long term growth potential that
the sector offers
we continue to remain focused on
building our business model
based on strong pillars of customer
excellence multi-channel distribution
prudent risk management technology
progress and capital conservation
i would like to thank you for attending
this earnings conference call
and we would be happy to take any
questions that you may have thank you
thank you very much we will now begin
the question and answer session
anyone who wishes to ask questions may
press star and one on the touchstone
telephone
if you wish to remove yourself from the
question q you may press star and two
participants are requested to use
handsets while asking questions
ladies and gentlemen we will wait for a
moment while the question q assembles
to ask a question please press star and
one
participants wish to ask questions may
press star and one on the touchstone
telephone
you take the first question from the
line of harsh torsion
from premg invest please go ahead
hi uh thanks for the opportunity
two questions firstly on the
health covert
[Music]
what further loss issue can we see in
the health system
uh and the second question is related to
tp losses so
it has come down to around 60 percent uh
over there can you explain a bit what
led to that resolving it is
in this
the total numbers that we gave hashita
is
inclusive of the indemnity claims and
the benefit claims uh if you remember we
had talked about the fact that we had
you know even before the regulator had
mandated we had launched a
low ticket uh small sum insured uh in
you know in benefit policy also
so the average acs for us will be lower
but the exact number in terms of the
total claims number i'll ask gopal to
give you in terms of the trend that we
see
as i explained our sense is that the
september number was
potentially the peak i mean the
incremental that data that we are
seeing in this month based on cashless
claims
we are seeing seeing some moderation uh
if that trend continues and uh
you know in a sense we september remains
a peak
then in aggregate the health loss ratio
numbers should be uh
you know reasonable we have had some
savings in the first half in terms of
non-covet claims
that would largely compensate the
concern remains which is very
you know difficult to predict concern
remains uh that if there is a second
spike which we've seen in other
countries or
as also you know driven by festivities
here
uh and that number is high that could be
a bit of a concern
but i think as i mentioned right at the
beginning i think overall when we look
at our overall portfolio
uh you know motor and you know other
corporate lines and health
i think it is a lot we are reasonably
confident about our claims cost
not uh you know crossing you know the
loss ratios of last year
if you remember one of the things that
we had talked about in the first quarter
also
was that there is a benefit that we are
seeing in terms of
incident rates low being lower and it
wouldn't be appropriate to
factor all of that benefit up front
which one could have
but we said we don't we want to wait for
the uh picture to
play through for the whole year and we
will spread this benefit over the years
which is what gives us a comfort that we
are you know
adequately cushioned in terms of our
aggregate claims cost for the year
um in terms of the specific numbers i'll
ask gopal to uh give you the case yeah
so just
one thing the way i was looking at if
it's 17 000
and even tickets
uh a gross number comes out to around
121.34
uh for forward claims just want to
understand that
in the quarter beyond that one twenty
one thirty crore of gold king
can we provide uh
there are two things that we have to
look at when we look at the total health
claims there is the
coveted numbers which we talked about
but there is a non-covered claims also
we are
watching the frequency and at least even
in q2 there has been some savings
so on balance we are quite fine for this
quarter
and as i said the benefit of first
quarter we did not feel that it was
appropriate to take the full benefit in
essence you can call it a kind of a
quasi reserve
that we've created which which should
help us
in this period so
if you remember i think in the quarter
one i think when the similar thing was
asked in terms of how many cases did we
get and what was the value corresponding
to that
i think we had kind of indicated that we
received in quarterback roughly about
1300 and
odd cases and the value concerned was
close to about 18 to 20 groups
this number when you look at it for the
half year as bargain said the total
number of claims that has been
reported to us is about roughly about 17
000 cases
and the amount corresponding to that is
about 115 crores
so in terms of uh how do we go about
the estimation of the loss reserves
obviously i think we always
factor in for any kind of prudence
that we have to build in as a part of
our loss ratio assumptions
particularly because there is always a
possibility of let's say
some lag in reporting that could happen
in so far as customer systems
that's one and secondly i think in terms
of the approach that we have taken
on building for loss ratios we have
always
tried to be a little conservative
keeping in mind the fact that there
could be
an increase in incidences which is where
uh even in quarter one
we had kind of uh while there were
benefits in the form of
reduction in claim frequency that we're
experienced but the fact that there
could be developments in the subsequent
quarters we kind of stayed put with
where
we are so hence it's not just that we
would have kind of factored in about 115
crores as a part of our
numbers for the half year we would
obviously kind of look at
what has been let's say the kind of uh
some kind of delayed
intimations so that's something that
gets built in and some level of prudence
also is built in as a part of our losses
assumptions
we might see some of it has already been
provided
so the key thing is
seems to be kind of indicating maybe
some reduction in number of cases
but honestly i think we would want to
wait and see how the
uh development happens post the festive
season
and to be honest the increase in the
number of cases
that one has seen particularly in
quarter 2
we would not have necessarily
anticipated to to that extent
and hence we would obviously want to
wait and see for the
next half in terms of if at all there is
a possibility of
a second uh wave of covet cases that's
what we
indicated even in the opening comments
and then we will to that extent um
calibrate the extent of uh loss ratio
assumptions that we are putting
okay and so largely on the conversation
so
so i didn't answer that part so
basically on tp uh
as you know our standard practices when
we uh again
part of our philosophy of being
conservative uh
this is a very typical best practice of
good insurance companies globally when
we
uh reserve we look at in a sense uh
very conservative reserving and only
when the data comes through
with lag do we release reserves whenever
we think we have a uh confidence that
the reserve is uh
realisable and we do this every quarter
with our actual team
and you know and and this quarter there
has been some
tp reserve releases but it's not
very large and we think that overall our
kind of overall benefit that we have we
still continue with the same practice of
being conservative about the
new book that we are writing
thank you before we take the next
question
we'd like to inform participants that in
order that the management is able to
address
questions from all participants in the
conference please limit your questions
to two paparazzism should you have
follow-up questions we request you to
rejoin the queue
we take the next question from the line
of mr sanket koda from
spark capital please go ahead
yeah thanks for the opportunity uh so
again my question is on motor third
party
because because one of your competitors
who announced the result
uh his uh their view is that given given
tribunals are not working uh the
interest component for severity will
substantially increase till till the
courts opens and give the rewards to the
claimants so so due to factoring the
risk they have started providing little
higher and then they usually
used to provide but but when when we
look our numbers mean that could be a
possible case for us also so so in that
sense uh the
tp loss ratio at 62 percentage in the
current quarter
or or for one hedge at around 66
percentage looks looks very
very impressive so just wanted to
understand
uh uh easy because because the frequency
has come off
uh that's why we are taking the benefit
or or is it because of some bit of motor
vehicle ad benefit because it has
completed one year
we have acted some bit of benefit or or
even we have now sell long term pp plans
and and the frequency naturally comes
out because of the higher denominator
base that is that that is getting
reflected into the numbers
they just wanted to understand that a
little more granularity on motor tp loss
issuance
of your trend going ahead and
yeah okay you have another one oh yeah i
have one more question
on health uh last time you gave the
breakup of
data keeping also last time you give the
breakup of total health around 800
crores what you did in current quarter
and
600 in the half uh broken down into pure
indemnity
uh and and retail internality and the
benefit based
so the second one i'll ask uh you know
gopal to answer but let me
address the first question uh so if
so you know i really can't comment off
on what others are doing but
our practice and we've always been
saying that
there are some companies which are
possibly taking a very aggressive
reserving call when they're disclosing
their numbers on the tp side
our approach has been just the opposite
we've always been very conservative as i
explained right at the beginning in
terms of when we reserve we
create a reserve for uh you know
potential adverse deviation
uh and that's a you know good practice
that you know i think insurance
companies should have
uh in this quarter there is no change in
our philosophy we are not taking any
benefit of
uh something that we do can't quantify
or estimate we will watch that
play through and as as we also explained
that beginning of the year itself we
said that we should not take the full
benefit of the either od or tp claims
because of the frequency losses because
we don't know what will happen in the
second half
so whatever the reason that has happened
in this quarter is largely because of
the data that we see over
years over the period of the bank book
and
you know so it could be because of maybe
overall frequency losses
in general in the system not because of
just the last one
uh you know you know one or two quarters
or
because of maybe less accidents or
because of the you know conservativeness
that we have in terms of reserving
as i explained the principle of being
conservative for the future remains
consistent so if you see our tp lost
issues in the past was significantly
higher than
you know some you know some of the
competitors that we are probably
studying
and maybe uh we are benefiting from that
today
while for others it may not be the case
okay from the breakdown of numbers uh
on the investor deck you would have seen
the uh
total uh premiums that you would have
given for health pa
and travel put together which was
roughly i'm giving you numbers for the
half year which was roughly about 16.88
billion
uh what we had seen for first half of
last year and the first half of this
year that number was about 15.94
if i were to split that within that
health is about 13.44 billion
for first half of last year and 14.26
billion
in so far as first of the current year
is concerned that includes
both the employer employee or let's say
the corporate health
and it also includes the retail health
component as well
now within the health breakdown
the overall retail health numbers that
we have
within the 13.44 and 14.26
the retail health for us which is again
a combination of both
indemnity and benefit together for the
first half last year is 7.29 billion
and first half of this year is about
5.97 billion
the breakup of which for indemnity
is 3.27 billion is the number for first
half last year
and 4.28 billion is the
numbers for the first half of the
current year the balance amount
pertains to the benefit component which
was roughly about 4.02 billion
in first half of last year as compared
to 1.7 billion for first off of the
currency
so effectively on the indemnities retail
indemnity side we have roughly about 30
or
30. 30.9 percent growth 30.9
growth and for benefit we have a
de-growth because these are usually
attachment policies that we sell with
uh nba c's hfcs and banker
okay perfect thanks so much that's it
for me
thank you the next question is from the
lion of deepak's
from i talk securities please go ahead
hello hi yeah my question is
sorry i couldn't hear the question
clearly gopal if you heard it can you
could you answer
me sorry deepak i think the same thing
at my end if you can just repeat the
question i can
respond to that appropriately sure sure
hello yeah just go ahead
yeah so recently as we know recently
iita has mandated
reinsurers to not enter into any capital
hearing with insurers
yes we just wanted to know whether
without the benefit product
that our company said with three
insurers are those policies or those
period policies are capital gearing
nature or not
so deepak i think this was also asked to
us because the circular had come
somewhere towards the end of the last
year
wherein iid had said exactly the point
that you rightly mentioned
i think we have done an assessment of
all the arrangements that we have had
and there is no such arrangement which
should qualify
as a capital gearing arrangement all our
reinsurance treaties that we have
entered into meets the test of risk
transfer and do not fall within the
criteria of capital gearing
as is put out by the regulator
okay so so my follow-up question was
regarding the same hill segment so for
health insurance segment
our company uh as we know that on
fireplaces
if you see if you see that our earnings
results as a percentage of nwb
is quite high around like 70 above over
the years
as compared to the peers which is uh at
a level of 50
or 45 to 50 percent so can you please
provide
a granularity or a reasoning for this
so honestly deeper unexpected risk
reserve is purely a function of
the policies that you would have
underwritten
through the year generally
let's say for companies like us where
relatively a large part of our premiums
comes through motor and health segments
and equally we do
get premiums from the corporate lines as
well but
in general if you look at the overall
mix motor and health put together
roughly constitutes
close to about 70 of the overall mix of
premiums that we write
and as we all know generally motor
specifically we get to see a large part
of the premiums being sourced
uh during the festive seasons which is
the later half of the year
and even retail health to that extent
also gets sourced
uh to a large extent towards the quarter
four of the financial period
commercial lines would obviously have a
risk start date which is more towards
the beginning of
quarter one so hence to the extent that
you are able to
have growth as what we have seen in the
past which is significantly driven by
growth in h2 of any particular financial
period
to that extent obviously the earnings
that would have happened with respect to
those premiums
will be only for let's say a period of
three to four months assuming that you
have evenly written the business in h2
of that year
and the remaining premiums will get
earned in the subsequent period
so hence to that extent which is why you
find let's say the
ur as a percentage of the nwp is
what it is i think from our standpoint i
think the way we look at monitoring
ourselves in terms of performance
is more as to what is the overall
combined ratios that we operate with
which factors in
elements of ur in the form of earned
premiums
and correspondingly what has been the
claim experience and expenses that we
have incurred so that's what we
typically look at but to answer your
point it's purely a function of
how your policies have been underwritten
through the year
thank you the next question is from the
line of shantanu chakravati from
edelweiss securities
please go ahead thank you for the
opportunity and congratulations to
management for
putting out a strong set of numbers uh i
have two
sets of questions first relate to the
medical indemnity business where
for this quarter you have posted 40 plus
growth
what i would really appreciate is if
you guys could give me some color on
what has led to this growth in terms of
one
is it agent ads that is are you seeing
the per agent selling increase uh both
in terms of volume
or how much of this is rising and
secondly
uh if you could see that if you could
give some color on whether there's an
overall demand tailwind which
the whole sector seem to be riding on
and if so how your market share is
developing
and what could be the full year number
that basically some
granular information and insights around
the
medical industry would be very useful uh
and the second question
uh relates uh to you know
your sme lines uh where uh growth seems
to be quite robust and it's a
distribution channel
that we have been investing in for a
period how how are you seeing csu
competition
shipping up there and you know
how much of it is market creation how
much of it is
market share transfer for you
uh thanks uh uh let me
uh start with the second question first
and on the health
uh i'll cover maybe at an overview level
and i'll ask sanjeev to give you more
granular details on the
sme side it's probably very difficult to
exactly identify how much is market
shaking and how much is
new to you know industry numbers but
uh obviously a large part of it is
market share gain
um and that is visible in terms of the
uh segment by segment i mean when i talk
about segments by segment i look at
product segment if you look at fire
engineering
you know marine liability every segment
we are gaining market share
and that's driven by large corporate as
also sme
but what we are also doing is with the
sme uh
agency i mean that's largely an agency
and small broker-driven
business there is a lot of work that we
do
in terms of giving you know
you know hand-holding them with new
categories of products so for example
uh you know liability is not something
that is very
you know commonly sold for a certain
category of corporates i mean and there
we do a lot of work with
our agents to you know build their
knowledge and capability
so what they bring in thereafter is
possibly new to uh
industry but my guess is that a large
part of the business that growth that we
are seeing is uh
largely market share shift uh that is
happening uh
driven largely by uh the entire
investment that we've made
in terms of digital servicing and claim
servicing
uh just to give you a couple of uh you
know points as i mentioned uh almost 90
or what 88 percent of our policies
on the sme side we do without paper as
in completely digital
uh we've done stuff like uh you know on
health endorsements which
for the industry is a lot of uh physical
effort
uh for ghi policies we've kind of again
digitized and automated that process and
almost 60
of the policies now we are seeing it
done through that
you know process so there's a lot of
effort that we've put in terms of
streamlining processes for the
distribution and on the claim service
and the risk management service that we
provide to our customers that's been the
other factor why
uh market share is shifting uh coming to
your question on
on health uh as you know we've been
investing and
investing both in terms of product uh
you know process as also
in terms of the distribution addition
that we have
done and gopal talked about the
number of agents that we've added in
this uh quarter
but uh for the year i mean these are all
pure stages because
uh you know because licensing
examination is stuck most of them are
coming in as pos agents but
finally they will all they are really
agents only
and so there's a distribution rollout
that is happening there is an investment
that we are making
and there is an incremental business
that agents are getting because of the
tailwind that
you talked about in terms of actual
further details
i'll ask you to share uh whatever he
wants to add
i think pretty much covered just a quick
uh update uh
this clearly uh decent children even if
you look at the industry number
as you rightly mentioned there's a
decent growth which can be witnessed
there are
typically two you know uh sorts of
community of planning one is the
multiline another is the
only standalone health companies both of
them have seen
significant growth for us uh the key
driver has been
which we have been telling we've you
know investors over the last couple of
years we've been building our agency
network uh
another key element that has helped us
in the growth is the
activation of the agent making them
active on ground uh
another thing which worked in our flavor
favor in a way which uh even
has covered the fact that we've been uh
sourcing all our policies
for some time back on the digital mode
and the current scenario
has kind of helped our agents to
actually close up
on a low touch basis digitally which has
also worked in our favor
we also believe that this particular
scenario should continue it's kind of
ebbed out it was at its peak
around four five months back not kind of
but still on the positive side at 25 30
percent growth and that should continue
to exhibit
over uh next few months because fear
plays a big role and current pandemic
actually has made people believe that
buying health insurance is
investment rather than expense i think
that change of mindset
will go a long way in terms of overall
uh health insurance and industry doing
well and consequent to that
keep at ics lombard doing well
thanks thanks for the responses guys i
mean
if i could just press you on that point
i mean it
probably most of the agents activated
over the last three to four months
wouldn't be directly contributing to top
line
so would it be fair to say that of say
the stock added over the last two years
in the last four or five months
their levels of volume generation have
gone up
significantly and if there's surprising
component also then
yeah so the contribution from the
existing partners who are there on an
incremental basis because the tailbane
definitely that plays a big role
plus to get the incremental addition in
terms of growth the new activation
straightaway hit that bucket technically
because they were not contributing in
the past so
both of them play a significant role but
if you have to divide that matrix in
terms of
if you have grown a new book at 40
percent probably 75 percent seventy
percent of that new book growth would
have come from the existing set of
agents for going more but there would be
a decent contribution of 30 35 percent
coming from new set of active agents
also
thank you before we move to the next
question a reminder to participants to
please limit your questions to two per
participant
should you have fallout questions we
request you to rejoin the queue
uh we take the next question from the
line of ninten from invest tech capital
please go ahead uh thanks for the
opportunity sir
the two questions one on the operating
expenses side uh there is a fair bit of
growth on opex
uh in this quarter on a yy basis uh
and uh then we have seen some reversal
of provisions so if you can just share
what has happened there and secondly on
the motor od side we have uh
gained a lot of market share in this
quarter uh while we understand the
pricing is pretty aggressive uh
in the in the sector uh so how do you
see
uh this strategy of getting market share
in an environment which i think is very
very very uh aggressive
yeah so let me answer the second one and
then i'll ask gopal to answer the first
one
uh look you know whatever do we do in
terms of market share
it will never be at the cost of uh
sustainability
uh so one of the things that we've uh
you know we keep doing is
uh uh doing a lot a lot of granular
analysis in terms of
new factors to select risk and
some of the experiments that we've been
doing over the last couple of years
in some of the uh you know
segments where we were a bit cautious
we've done some more work
so some new opportunities have opened up
whether it will sustain or not i think
if the aggression continues maybe we'll
slow down a bit
but till now whatever we've grown is
largely because of selection where we
like
in fact even if you see the overall
growth there are uh
you know a couple of interesting
pictures that are emerging one is
the fact that uh in some of the oems
where we believe the pricing has reached
a unviable level actually we've cut down
in two wheelers in private car we've
actually cut down uh
two of the you know larger oems
while elsewhere we've grown secondly the
auto ninja investment that we did last
year
that is really helping us with the
renewals and wherever the dealers we've
kind of entered in
the renewal book is doing well thirdly
the agency investment and the virtual
office investment that we've
that we made couple of years back or
over the last couple of years
that's doing really well so the older
book is also growing for us where
our relative market share was small or
lower and the vo virtual office we had
almost a 50 percent growth in this
uh in this period so that is also
helping
uh enter into markets where we were
relatively
uh underpenetrated so on the only side
we are reasonably
comfortable with the book that we are
writing on the course i'll ask gopal to
answer
yeah i think uh let me just kind of give
the macro picture first i think if you
look at i think the way
um i'm sure we all look at is what kind
of expense ratios have we run
when you kind of break down the combined
ratio of 99.7 percent that we reported
for quarter two or let's say 99.8 for
the first half of the year um if you
look at the expense ratios
just the opex numbers uh for quarter two
last year the expense ratios were twenty
five point three percent
if you look at this quarter two it said
twenty six percent
and even if you look at it on a half
year to half year basis
i think it was twenty three point nine
and it at about 25.7
so clearly i think uh um as
growth has started to come back i think
what we also explained last time
um there is also an element of a
denominator effect that starts to have a
bearing in so far as
expense ratios are concerned which is
why uh the quarter two will be a far
more
uh representation of uh the uh expense
ratios which
is more or less staying at about twenty
five point three as compared to twenty
uh to twenty six percent
now within that i think in line with
what we spoke even in quarter one
if you one was to kind of break down
what we had indicated clearly was
we would want to continue to make
investments in
uh technology and uh to that extent one
of the points that vargo mentioned
we did have an acquisition of auto ninja
that came through
in quarter three last year that
obviously entails an element of
a depreciation charge that we have to
take uh
on month and obviously the benefits is
something that will play through over a
period of time
which obviously did not find a reference
when you look at quarter two of last
year so that's one element of
expense which is there in quarter two
this year as compared to quarter two of
the previous year
secondly we are continuing to make
investments in
various digital initiatives as what we
outlined even as a part of our
introductory
comment including also making available
various
digital uh avenues for
even our employees to work with so
so the thrust has been on incurring cost
with respect to
technology and digital initiatives so to
that extent one has obviously seen an
increase
in cost with respect to that particular
cost item
having said that what we had also
indicated is we would obviously
keep a check on all other elements of
cost whether it is with respect to our
infrastructure
or other admin related expenses there
i think one can one has clearly seen
a improvement in the overall cost
by almost about 10 compared to what you
would have seen on a quarter to quarter
basis so which is why
in the aggregate it's a mix of both
there are those
uh items of course which is
incrementally there in this quarter
and the fact that we are making some of
those continued investments in
technology capabilities which is to some
extent balanced by
the efficiencies that we have been able
to get on the infra and
the administrative expenses
so the answer on the provision reversal
and
the other expenses that we have
so other expenses if you are referring
to expenses
other than those relating to insurance
business if that is what you are
referring to
which would have seen an increase uh
when you look at over sequential
quarters
uh if that's is that what you're
referring to
yeah let's explain that yeah if that is
what you're referring to
uh you will definitely see an increase
on expenses other than insurance
business which would have seen a spike
in quarter two this year as compared to
quarter one or even
let's say quarter two of last year
that's primarily because one of the
points what we
indicated as a part of the opening
remarks was with respect to
the cost of the de-merger expenses which
is roughly about 31 crores
that has been taken as a charge to the
pnl and that finds a reference
under the line item which is expensive
other than those relating to insurance
business in the profit
profit loss statement
sure that's it for my site
thank you the next question is from the
line of uh
from ambit capital please go ahead
uh thank you sir thank you sir uh
i the question i had was if i you know
just roughly
uh you know take an average claim uh you
know
in terms of covid uh that amount was
roughly around
1.5 to 1.6 lakhs last quarter but
uh for this quarter it has you know come
down more than half to around 67
68 000 so uh
what has led to this because i remember
last quarter
you had mentioned or the management has
mentioned that there is some kind of
you know standardization being talked
through uh you know
a lot of lobbying is going around that
so what has
gone into this or is it that the average
stays
in hospital have gone down and the
second question is if you could give
some color
on the solvency uh you know why it has
improved
that will be helpful so the second one
again i'll
ask gopal to answer on the first it's a
mix of all of that
uh one is the fact that uh
when as an industry we've negotiated uh
you know rates
not that every hospital has come on
board but uh
in aggregate there's a lot more
sensitivity and there is uh
you know a certain chunk of hospitals
who
come on board in terms of uh agreeing on
to these package rates
number two if you see the mix in the
second
half of this year we have uh some of
those low ticket benefit
uh policies that we had written that
those claims have come through so
uh while we've got uh you know
some reduction in the rates on the
indemnity claims because of
uh both the negotiation as also the fact
that
uh less critical of individing less you
know
critical cases we are seeing releases
you know people length of stays coming
down et cetera
so there is a benefit of the inability
side plus on a mixed side we've had a
larger
share of the small ticket benefit uh
you know claims also which is why the
average uh
looks much lower so if you look at in
terms of number of cases we have
almost five percent market share but in
terms of number of uh in terms of
premium or in terms of claims
we are probably about three percent of
the industry
numbers it's largely because of a mix of
business a larger share of benefit
claims it's a small
small ticket
and on the point with respect to
the solvency i think solvency is purely
a function of uh
what kind of uh businesses that you
write
and uh corresponding and as and then you
would have seen that uh
even when you look at it on a half year
basis uh the growth for us
has been at about let's say 0.8 percent
which obviously given the kovid
situation
it has been a kind of a moderate growth
and hence that obviously has a direct
bearing
with respect to your solvency outcome
and the second obviously
it's a function of your operating
performance as well
i think we have been able to uh sustain
the operating performance in terms of uh
as i said the combined ratios of around
100 and that also by itself
kind of contributes uh and the fact that
we have been able to also report
uh a profits of almost about 814 crores
for the half year
which equally kind of adds on to the
solvency number so it's purely a
function of once
we will start to see let's say
incremental levels of uh
growth coming in then obviously it
starts to have
a bearing uh in so far as the solvency
is concerned so that's one
and secondly i think uh we did have some
amount of
uh let's say government receivables of
the crop business that we had
underwritten
in 2018 2019 some of which were
outstanding and obviously that does have
an impact uh beyond a particular period
in case it
remains uh as receivable so we have also
seen
certain collections of uh premiums that
we have received in this first half year
of course corresponding to which there
has also been a payout
but in terms of the admissibility of
certain receivables beyond a particular
period that has come down so it's a it's
a combination of
all those three factors in terms of
premium the extent of
receivables that will be available as an
admissible asset
and the overall improved operating
performance
thank you the next question is from the
line of
suresh kanpathy from macquarie please go
ahead
yeah hi thanks most of my questions have
been answered just wanted to double
check
you know your loss rates um in the first
half of course is even lower than what
what it was in the first quarter on an
overall basis
so this is despite higher claims that
you have experienced so
you know um the full year last year
number was about
you know 72 73 odd percent so what you
are telling here is that
despite the higher claims possibly um
which could happen in the second half
you are very confident that the
full your loss rates uh for this year
would still be kept below
fr 20 levels right is that the way to
look at it
so we are not giving anything about the
exact percentage for the year but what
we are saying is that
we were very careful and conservative
about the
way we treated the frequency drops in
the first quarter
and something that we've seen continue
for q2
and that benefit will help us over the
over the full year because
as frequency increases in the second
half we don't see
the claims number spiking uh
significantly and that was
what we had talked about in the first
quarter as well that we are being
careful about
estimating the full benefit in the first
quarter quarter itself so we will see
that play through what the reason why we
don't want to give you a complete
guidance is
uh a bit of uncertainty about uh what
happens with
the second covet spike if we don't then
we have more certainty but who knows
what happens
post the uh posie uh festive season
and uh you know bhagav of course uh this
question was answered in the previous uh
this thing
about the lower covert ticket sizes
claims um
in the second quarter i think even if
there is a spike in cases we can assume
the same proportion
um i know it's a very difficult question
but then i'm just
i'm just trying to understand that
there's no reason why there should be a
certain
significant change yeah in the effort to
uh
you know get more hospitals to agree on
the package rates the effort to
negotiate uh you know the effort that we
are putting in terms of
uh you know identifying uh you know
fraudulent claims etc
will be ongoing and in fact you know
this year we uh we launched an upgraded
uh
ml based fraud uh you know monitoring uh
solution
and we are seeing some benefit out of
that so there's a lot of effort that we
put to contain some of these things
so i guess you know unless there's some
unpleasant surprise
in terms of second spike we remain
reasonably confident about our loss
ratio numbers
thank you the next question is from the
line of abhishek sarah from jeffrey's
india
please go ahead yeah hi
thanks for the opportunity uh several of
my questions have been answered
if you think in the process so so i see
that uh our
loss ratios in uh fire portfolio have
actually risen despite the fact that we
have been taking
significant price high uh i understand
some of it could be because
it has to be playing so but if you can
just let me
understand better why is it happening
that there's a lot of issues
in fire uh despite the strength right uh
certainly
uh uh uh if you can just give us an
update on the
birthday station where
yeah so on the first you know fire will
always be a bit
sporadic because there are two types of
clips the high severity claims
as also the frequency claims on
frequency claims we are seeing
significant benefit because of price
increase
high severity claims are typically the
cash losses are very
you know large losses that come through
now for us
the first half we had more catalans
because of
in q1 we had cyclones normally that is
reserved for q2 and q2 we continue to
have
flood losses but on balance when we kind
of look at our numbers and predict the
fire portfolio we believe by the end of
the year
we should see some improvement uh you
know i'm just caveating that by
you know to the extent that at times in
fire it's very difficult to break
because some
some catastrophe you cannot prevent a
predict but otherwise we are quite
satisfied with the with the trend that
we are seeing in our
non-severity uh claims on the fireside
so we are reasonably
comfortable over a fire book
in terms of the way the deal is
progressing at this point in time
it is on track uh you know we are
awaiting cci clearance before we
can go to the next stage um but
we think we are online or rather in
online with whatever we had assumed in
terms of progress
uh we will know when the cci comes in
uh about the next steps
okay just one question if i think
if you can help me understand that what
what happens is i think this is
something that we
explained even when we had kind of taken
this
impairment provision uh in quarter four
of uh last year
we do have an investment impairment
policy which kind of tests
stocks for impairment and basis which
depending on the market moment we are
required to take a charge and prediction
we make a provision in the books
however subsequently as and when let's
say we would obviously have a view
on each stock in terms of uh at what
point of time we would want to
take an exit uh so in case if the exit
of the stock happens corresponding to
that
whatever impairment provisions have been
recognized
in the past those would obviously get
reversed
and the actual realization will be given
effect with respect to
either a gain or loss on account of sale
of that particular stock
so in this particular half here we did
have
let's say an impairment on on one of our
equity stocks which we had created
in the last year which has been kind of
realized and that's where you see
a reversal of the impairment and
correspondingly the actual
realization has been given effect in the
pnm
thank you the next question
is from the line of kamal varma from
morgan stanley please go ahead
yes i just one question that was on the
motor portfolio so on the commercial
vehicle segment part of it
and uh like lombard has been uh
traditionally
not as not has been has not been as
focused on the commercial vehicle
part as much as the private current two
wheeler part
so what is the reason for that and how
would you
like how attractive or an attractive is
this segment versus private car into
just in terms of competition fighting
loss ratios and
renewals it can just throw some light on
that
yeah so our view has been that i mean if
you look at the industry mix
in general i have you know don't look at
just this last six months number because
it's uh
kind of not reflective of general
industry picture
but if you look at the industry mix uh
you know private car would be roughly
about 40 45 percent of the mix
uh cvs would be uh again a similar
number maybe 45 plus
and two wheelers would be about 15 for
the industry
uh for us uh you know cv has been about
of our mix um private car has been
roughly about 50 55 percent of our mix
and two wheelers has been
uh between 25 to 30 of our mix uh
largely because we believe these are uh
you know more profitable segments based
on our experience
having said that on the cv side uh i
kind of touched upon this point earlier
also but what we've been doing over the
last two two years two years is that
we are doing a lot more uh work on the
micro segmentation of the cv book
and uh post the new motor vehicle act
there are certain segments that we
believe
uh make sense uh to underwrite uh and cv
the big issue is tp not necessarily the
odps
so on the tp if the book is you know
viable then we would want to write it so
we are gradually increasing our cv book
but very very selectively we will not
go anywhere near the industry mix i mean
from 15
will maybe move it up a little bit but
our overall view of what
aggregate cv book remains uh while as i
said
with the new motor vehicle act we
believe certain uh sectors or certain
sub-segments of cv
could become more attractive so we are
gradually looking at uh
increasing our cv exposure very very
marginally
any particular like segments which you
want to highlight are
becoming more yeah no we don't want to
give any more details because it's
comparative information
so those are selection
criteria for us thank you
thank you the next question is from the
line of deepika mundra from jp morgan
please go ahead uh hi sir and thanks for
taking my question
um i'm sorry this is a very basic one
but just on the health side
uh given the sharp growth that you're
seeing in indian military uh
some are relatively uh new agency school
uh on an overall postcode level how are
you
avoiding adverse uh this selection as
this
segment becomes more meaningful for you
uh look because it's uh that's a great
question but it's not as if
we were not writing uh you know uh
chi from the agency channel in the past
it was just that
uh in the past since we didn't have the
flexibility of repricing we were a bit
cautious
and we also had a constraint before the
pos
regulation came in in terms of adding
agency so both were the
you know those are the two constraints
which went away around 2015-16 and
that's when we started
uh focusing on the segment i think
couple of you know if you look at over
the last
uh you know from 2003 for
the capabilities that we've built in
terms of uh fraud control
and network management is there it's not
as if
we didn't have the capability and uh
when we are looking at some of these
agents it's not as if they are new to
the industry uh
you know they may be you know they are
maybe existing agents we are of course
adding some new to the industry agents
also
but we are you know we are we are also
attracting some of the existing agents
now on the underwriting side our filters
are probably a bit more stringent than
most
uh so and when we look at the
viability of that portfolio we don't
look at it from a short-term perspective
our actual team and underwriting team do
a lot of work in terms of the long-term
viability of the portfolio when we
underwrite
what i mean by that is as you know the
initial period the
exposure is less because of the uh you
know
two year or four year wait period and
then the loss picks up
and you have to study the loss ratio
pattern of a cohort over
let's say eight ten years to figure out
whether the portfolio will be viable
over that period
uh that's how we we study it when we
kind of review it together
as a team we study the long term uh
you know loss ratio a pattern of this
book and
we have lot of tools that we have in
terms of uh
selection so yes uh it's something that
is
very important it's not a uh you know
no it's not an unimportant question at
all it's a very very important question
that you've asked
but that's something that we focus a lot
on
okay and so if i can just um follow up
to that it just seems that the regulator
is uh leaning towards widening the net
in terms of the number of diseases
covered and that
you know uh policies becoming slightly
more comprehensive in nature uh
do you think all those uh litigations
are you know priced in the current
crisis framework
so they allowed when they you know and
when they asked us to increase they
allowed us to
also increase prices to a small extent
uh but
as we've you know given in our
presentation
we've also have regulatory approval for
our
retail chi flagship chi product while
there's wider coverage there's also
price
revision we would uh you know kind of
from november onwards
all new customers uh we would switch to
the new uh
new pricing and for our renewal book
we'll switch from
january so the regular has been i think
pretty balanced and they're they're
sensitive to
this issue of course we have to show
them data and convince them why we need
price increase
but which is in my opinion quite fair
and reasonable but
if there is a requirement it's not as if
they don't allow price increases
okay and so what would this price
increase from november amount to
that would be roughly about seven eight
percent right on our way but
on a weighted average basis on the
portfolio will be roughly about seven
seven to eight percent
okay thank you so much
thank you the next question is from the
line of pratik podar from
nippon india mutual fund please go ahead
yeah hi so just wanted to check uh could
you is it possible for you to share what
was the exit growth rates of
benefit-based health products and
indemnity products
and second is uh is there been a
material change in the distribution
makes for the industry slash itself
post covered or it's the same as it was
pre-covered and lastly sir on the
digital initiatives uh you did uh talk
about it
i just wanted to understand with this
way you are presented on slide then the
scale up of these initiatives
uh how should we think about uh expense
ratios from a medium term perspective
so maybe the first two questions i'll
ask sanjeev to answer on the on the
last point uh honestly the
entire effort for us is uh you know in
terms of
employee productivity as also uh uh
customer convenience and
uh reduction in error rates right so
that's it's not just productivity
that we look at and if you look at over
the last 12 years
they're in the same slide our employee
productivity has been us
15 cage year and if you look at our
total head count today is much less than
what we had in 2008
while our policy numbers have grown
eight times roughly
um and that's been made possible because
of the tech investment that we've made
over the years not just what i talked
about in the opening remarks
going forward uh the the aspects that we
are focusing on
is why for the customer side there's a
lot of a customer or
agency or distributor we've done a lot
of work
uh in terms of digitizing processes and
and making it convenient
there is still some more work that we
could potentially do uh
you know in terms of you know human
judgment which is
where the aiml solution comes in which
probably eliminates some of the routine
work that
our doctors do when it comes to let's
say health claims
but then gives them the ability to do
more work on the portfolio analysis etc
and that's where we should we should see
the benefit and
honestly when we scale you know as we
scale we will not
need to add as many people as uh in line
with
uh you know the the uh the uh you know
business growth
so that's why you know if you look at
the last 12 years you see the
data that i talked about in terms of you
know policy count versus
head count reduction uh in terms of um
in terms of the health pattern i'll ask
sanjeev
no i think your spot on clearly as we
have been always telling every investor
that uh our health book was more stewed
towards the benefit construct uh visited
the indemnity and
over the last actually couple of years
this kind of
has gone through a change we have a huge
bank assurance partnership which works
through the
nbfc and banks uh last since last year
nbfcs have been very restrictive on
their disbursements and
in this year first half of the year also
even banking while they have recovered
banks have
generally recovered to some extent the
quarter two and quarter one was fairly
subdued
that extend the contribution of the
benefit book has gone through a change
in the overall health book
typically we've been saying that almost
you know two-thirds of our book used to
get driven through
benefit on vacation startups uh however
that has transformed an intimidating
book has increased
and has also seen a lot of sales and
growth so
there has been a shift it's not that it
was done by design there has been
circumstances by which the uh integrity
has gone up but we were prepared for
both opportunities to be fair and
since we had been investing on the
endemic side uh we've been able to grow
on
that part and as and when the nbfc
stroke banking sector start disbursing
even on the benefit attachment part we
would see
reasonable growth for ourselves which
has been subdued otherwise over nothing
sorry if i make interrupt my question
was honestly in the month of september
because i understand there will be
sequential recovery i was just looking
at the exit growth rates for the quarter
for the benefit base how's the trend
been and same for indemnity
okay so initiality i think we continue
to witness recent growth i covered that
when i spoke uh
yeah then i don't see that changing
substantially and typically indian media
book has a much better
growth for the industry itself in the
second half so
we should continue to see that on
benefits side as i speak i spoke about
it we do believe that it will have a
much better without getting into very
much specific details we would see much
better numbers in the second half as
what happened in the first half of the
year for sure
okay answer question on distribution mix
if if has there been any change in the
distribution exposed covered or it's the
same as pre-coverage
for the industry and this mix can be
attributed to the fact that we are doing
more information
through which is done through agent's
solutions and digital more preservatives
bank assurance was done through banking
partner
to that extent has gone to a uh through
a bit of a transformation but is it
something by design by choice i think
some bit of uh lack of growth in the
beneficial side has impacted that but it
should come back so we are pretty much
invested on both sides
so i don't think you should i think the
point that sanjiv is making don't take
the
uh you know the current numbers and uh
assume that will continue
i think as the npfcs and the banks come
back into the
disbursement our mix will again probably
go back a bit more in favor of
benefit not to the extent that we had in
the past i just wanted to check for the
whole company not from the health
perspective if uh honestly whether
website traffic or
uh direct businesses increase for you
or website
yes we have seen a significant
improvement on the health
side on motor as well as two wheeler it
has remained
neutral to positive uh at this point of
time but
uh clearly in time to come the way we'll
be investing we may see some growth but
any substantial shift in terms of
percentage contribution of website
that's what happened as yet
okay so the online channel still
continues to be minuscule
or or very small as a percentage of our
sales right it's
traditional channels which are still
leading the growth yes yes
thank you we'll be able to take one last
question
we take the last question from the line
of ajax frederick
from bnk securities please go ahead
uh sir thanks for the opportunity again
sorry to hop
on this moto tp uh
what's your outlook with respect to
claims so going forward now that
we've almost reached very good numbers
on loss ratios
so how should i see it moving forward
look uh you know as i explained you
should not look at just the quarterly
numbers we should look
at a more longer period because as i
explained and we've been saying it
uh over most calls that there would be
certain quarters where
based on our analysis there could be
some releases in the quarter
what you should watch for is a ytd
number and you know probably see it
over the over the years over the full
year now
in terms of uh where we are seeing the
pp
uh book um i think overall we are
uh you know reasonably uh confident
about the tp book also because of the
new motor third party uh you know act
that has come in
um we are not as yet uh
kind of making a full benefit out of
that but at least early sciences we
think there should be a
there should be a benefit how much of
that will play through we will have to
wait to see
um so overall i think the tp book looks
largely okay as long as we remain
careful but don't go by just a quarter
number because that
there will be some volatility because of
releases in a quarter
uh versus no releases in another quarter
understood surrounding provisions being
released uh
particularly with respect to investment
so we
we can see and the benefit of close to
50 codes coming in
uh maybe if markets have been buoyant
sorry uh maybe gopal you want to argue
the provision reversals we did it for
this quarter
uh since markets uh have been point
uh so 74 hours of reversal happened so
we had provided up close to
120 crore in 4q so the remaining 50
crores we can see that happening
uh anytime soon no as we as i had
explained
i think the we do have an investment
impairment policy that we
uh get guided by and in quarter 4 last
year we did provide for that 1.2 billion
because clearly we saw
significant volatility in the market
value of stocks corresponding to the
cost that we were holding and hence we
had to kind of make
a provision of 1.2 billion as i said in
so far as this half year is concerned
obviously we we take views on
the portfolio of stocks that we hold and
in case if we believe
a particular stock has reached a value
which we think is appropriate
then we would kind of exit from the
stock and in case if that results into
any form of gain then we would realize
the gains
and if at all for some reason if the
call on the stock has been not correct
then to the direction we may book a loss
and done every bit so that's how
you what you see in so far as the p l is
concerned when you are seeing
a reversal of provision for impairment
which is what i explained in this half
year the
one of the stocks that we had kind of
impaired for uh during the half year
i think we had a view on the stock and
at this point of time
we have kind of exited from the stock
and the actual realization
has been kind of booked for through the
pnl
so also so kind of to add to what gopal
is saying uh if you look at our
fair value change account for equity you
will see a uh
you know increase that doesn't mean that
it lost the pnl
if we believe a particular stock has
reached its uh
pricing potential that we foresee and
and we sell it
then only we will uh look at uh you know
booking again
otherwise we'll just stay as that
farewell
thank you
thank you very much we'll take that as
the last question
i would now like to hand the conference
back to mr balcombe for closing comments
thank you raymond and thank you guys uh
stay safe
take care of yourself all the best good
night
thank you everyone thank you thank you
thank you very much on behalf of icici
lombard general insurance
that concludes this conference thank you
for joining us ladies and gentlemen
you will now disconnect your lines
you